Hello again. In this video we're gonna wrap up our overview of cool with one more
又见面了。在这个视频中，我们将用另外一个来结束我们对酷的概述
example of writing a cool program. For our final example, let's look at a program
写一个很酷的程序的例子。对于我们的最后一个示例，让我们看一个程序
that actually manipulates some interesting data structure. So we'll begin here by
这实际上操作了一些有趣的数据结构。所以我们从这里开始
opening up a file. And let's call our program list dot CL this time. And as
打开一个文件。让我们这次将我们的程序列表命名为.CL。以及AS
usual, I will begin by writing our main routine, and our main method. And once
通常，我会从写我们的主要例程开始，我们的主要方法。只有一次
again let's, let's make this inherit from I/O so we can do the I/O routines here.
再一次，让我们让它继承I/O，这样我们就可以在这里执行I/O例程。
And let's just begin with something very simple, as always. Let's just have
让我们从一些非常简单的事情开始，一如既往。我们只要有
something that prints out 'quot;Hello World'quot; but in a little bit of an unusual way.
打印出“你好，世界”的东西，但打印的方式有点不同寻常。
Let's, we're going to end up writing a list, a list abstraction. And let's first
让我们最后写一个列表，一个列表抽象。让我们首先
build a list by hand, or at least build the elements of a list by hand, and then
手动构建列表，或者至少手动构建列表的元素，然后
we'll actually build the list abstraction and put them in a list. So, let's have
我们将实际构建列表抽象并将其放入列表中。所以，让我们
some strings. So we will have our string hello, and this will also illustrate how
一些弦。因此，我们将拥有字符串hello，这也将说明如何
you do multiple LET bindings simultaneously. I shouldn't say
您可以同时执行多个let绑定。我不应该说
simultaneously. How you do multiple LET bindings in one LET expression. So you do
同时。如何在一个let表达式中实现多个let绑定。所以你就这么做了
them by just listing them, and notice that this uses commas as a separator rather
只列出它们，注意这使用逗号作为分隔符，而不是
than semicolons as a terminator. So this left binding is going to define three
而不是用分号作为终结符。所以这个左边的绑定将定义三个
names. Hello, world, and new line, all of which are strings. And then We're going to
名字。大家好，WORLD和NEW LINE，它们都是字符串。然后我们要去
now print these out on the screen, so we are going to want to be able to do out
现在将这些打印到屏幕上，所以我们希望能够将它们打印出来
string, and since main inherits from self, we can do that without an object there,
字符串，由于main继承自self，因此我们可以在没有对象的情况下完成该操作，
because it just, again, dispatches to the self object. And we want to concatenate
因为它只是，再一次，分派给Self对象。我们想要串联起来
these strings together in the right order. So we'll do hello dot, and since hello is
这些字符串以正确的顺序连接在一起。所以我们要做hello dot，既然hello是
a string, it can be concatenated to world, and world is a string, so it can be
一个字符串，它可以连接到world，而world是一个字符串，所以它可以
concatenated to newline And that should do the job. And just like probably one more
连接到换行符，这应该可以完成任务。就像可能再多一个
thing about this lead this, these lead bindings here. This notice if it, the
关于这个引线，这些引线绑定在这里。这张通知如果是这样的话，
comma is, the comma is the separator here, meaning it doesn't come after the last one
逗号是，逗号是这里的分隔符，意思是它不在最后一个之后
on the list. So it just separates that into the list, so it's not a terminator.
在名单上。所以它只是把它分隔到列表中，所以它不是终结符。
And now we can close up our main procedure. Close up our class definition.
现在我们可以结束我们的主要程序了。关闭我们的类定义。
Save it and now see if it compiles. Oh amazing! First try. And we run it, and it
保存它，现在看看它是否可以编译。哦，太棒了！先试一试。我们运行它，它
prints hello world, as expected. So now, let's, instead of introducing the three
不出所料，打印hello world。所以现在，让我们不介绍这三位
strings separately, and then concatenating them together, let's write an abstraction
字符串分开，然后将它们连接在一起，让我们编写一个抽象
where we can build a list of strings. And then that abstraction will have a function
在那里我们可以建立一个字符串列表。那么这个抽象就会有一个功能
within it to do the, to do the concatenation. Alright, so we'll have a
在它里面做，做连接。好的，那么我们将有一个
class called list. And, every list needs to, I think, to have two components. So
类名为List。而且，我认为每个清单都需要有两个组成部分。所以
first, it's gonna have the item that's in the list, and that'll be a string. And
首先，它将包含列表中的项目，这将是一个字符串。和
then when you have a pointer to the next, to the, to the tail of the list, to the
然后，当您有指向下一个、指向列表尾部、指向
rest of the list. And so I have a next, field that, points or is another list, is
睡觉榜上有名。所以我有一个下一个字段，它指向或者是另一个列表，是
another list of strings. Now we need a couple of methods in order to, in order to
另一个字符串列表。现在我们需要几种方法，以便
use this list. We'll need to be able to initialize a list in some way. So the
使用此列表。我们需要能够以某种方式初始化列表。因此，
initialization function will take an item and, the rest of the list, the next part
初始化函数将获取一项，并将列表的睡觉作为下一部分
of the list. And, what is it going to do? Well it's gonna need to set the fields of
在名单上。那么，它要做什么呢？嗯，它需要设置
the object, And so this one has to be done as a series of assignment statements. So
对象，所以这个必须作为一系列赋值语句来完成。所以
we'll need a statement block and we will set the item to be the I argument. We'll
我们需要挡路声明，并将该项设置为i参数。我们会
set the next, attribute to be the N argument. And now, we actually want, this
将下一个属性设置为N参数。而现在，我们实际上想要的是，这个
initialized object here, this, this method here, to return the object itself. So
这里初始化的对象，这里的this，this方法，返回对象本身。所以
that, and that'll be convenient for chained together calls to [inaudible]. So
这样，就可以方便地将呼叫链接到[听不见]。所以
we'll have it return self. It'll return the self object. And that's the end of out
我们会把它送回赛尔夫的。它将返回Self对象。这就是出局的终点
statement block. And then that is the end of our method. And, I made a mistake up
挡路声明。然后我们的方法就到此为止了。而且，我犯了个错误
here. We've gotta declare the return type of a knit. And what it's going to return
这里。我们必须声明针织的退货类型。以及它会带来什么回报
of course, it returns a, a object of type list. I'll need to put a list declaration
当然，它返回一个，一个List类型的对象。我需要写一份清单声明
there. Alright, so that takes care of, of a knit . And now we can use this to build,
那里。好的，这就解决了，针织的问题。现在我们可以用它来建造
build a list down here. So what should we do? Let's actually have a new variable
在这下面列一张单子。那我们该怎么办呢？让我们实际拥有一个新的变量
called list. That we'll introduce here in this lead, this series of lead bindings.
呼叫列表。我们将在这里介绍这一系列的引线绑定。
And let's just build a list out of these three objects. So we'll say, we'll have a
让我们从这三个对象中创建一个列表。所以我们会说，我们会有一个
new list, and then we'll initialize to contain the string hello. And. What should
新列表，然后我们将初始化以包含字符串hello。和。应该做些什么
the, rest of the list be? Well that should be another list, which is initialized to
那么，榜单上的睡觉是什么呢？那应该是另一个列表，它被初始化为
have the string the world. And what should be inside of that list file, is another
拥有这根弦的世界。该列表文件中应该包含的内容是另一个
new list object, which we'll initialize to have new line. And now what do we put
New List对象，我们将对其进行初始化，使其具有新行。现在我们该怎么做呢
here, actually there's a little bit of problem here isn't there? We need to put a
这里，实际上这里有一点问题，不是吗？我们需要把一个
list object here. But we don't want to allocate a, a new list object, we want
在此列出对象。但是我们不想分配一个新的列表对象，我们想
that to be really the equivalent of a, of a null pointer. And there's no name for
这实际上等同于，空指针的。而且也没有名字
that in Cool actually, you can't write down the name of a null pointer. It's
实际上，在Cool中，你不能写下空指针的名称。它是
called void in Cool. There's no, there's no, no special symbol for that. So we'll
被称为“凉爽中的空虚”。没有，没有，没有特殊的符号。所以我们会
have to create a variable that is just not initialized. And that will be, as well,
必须创建一个未初始化的变量。这也将是，同样的，
uninitialized variable of type list will, in fact be void. It'll be a null pointer.
List类型的未初始化变量实际上将为void。它将是空指针。
So let's call that nil. And it'll be a typed list, and no initializer. And so nil
那我们就称它为零吧。它将是一个类型化的列表，没有初始值设定项。所以是零
there will point to nothing or the, the void point. And then we can use nil to
什么都不会指向，或者是空白点。然后我们可以使用nil来
terminate our list here. And then we have to close off all the params for all the
我们的名单到此为止。然后我们必须关闭所有的参数
nesting here. And I think that's it. And so that will be our list. Okay, so we have
在这里筑巢。我想就是这样了。这将是我们的清单。好的，所以我们有
a list of three strings. And now what we want to do with that is to print it out.
包含三个字符串的列表。现在我们要做的就是把它打印出来。
And so what we would like to do is to have a list fall off the list, and then a
因此，我们想要做的是从列表中删除一个列表，然后一个
function that's gonna flatten that list and we'll just print it. So that is the
函数，该函数将扁平该列表，我们将直接打印它。所以这就是
what the, what the main program should do. And now. You have to write the flatten
主程序应该做什么。现在呢。你得写出平面图
function. So flatten takes no arguments. And it's going to return a string. It's
功能。所以Flatten不需要任何参数。它将返回一个字符串。它是
going to return a single string. And flatten is a pretty simple function. U h,
将返回单个字符串。而展平是一个相当简单的功能。嗯，
what do we have to do. Well. There's really two cases. One is if we're at the
我们要做什么。井。实际上有两个案子。一是如果我们在
end of the string, and the other is if we're not yet at the end of the string. So
字符串的末尾，另一个是如果我们还没有到达字符串的末尾。所以
let's, test for that. So how do we know if we're at the end of the string? Well, if
我们来测试一下。那么我们怎么知道我们是不是走到了最后呢？嗯，如果
the next pointer is, is void, then there is no, nothing more in the string. And
下一个指针是，是空的，那么字符串中就没有了。和
there actually is a special test for that in Cool. It's called the isvoid, function,
事实上，在Cool中有一个特别的测试来测试这一点。它被称为isvoid，函数，
and it's written like this. So if isvoid, of next, okay? So [inaudible] next field.
它是这样写的。所以如果是无效的，下一个，好吗？所以[听不见]下一场。
So if the next field is void, then what are we going to return? Keeps. Well then
那么如果下一个字段是空的，那么我们要返回什么呢？一直保持着。那好吧，那么
the result here is just, the item, whatever the item was in this last element
这里的结果就是项目，不管最后一个元素中的项目是什么
of the list. And otherwise What we want to do, Well, otherwise, we want to take the
在名单上。另外，我们想要做的是，嗯，否则，我们想要
item and we want to concatenate onto it, the result of flattening the rest of the
项目，我们想要连接到它上，这是将睡觉展平的结果
list. And that is our flattened method. So let's see if that works. So let's compile
列表。这就是我们的扁平化方法。所以让我们看看这是否奏效。所以让我们编译一下
this. And we got a couple of syntax errors here. So let's go back and see what's
这。我们这里有几个语法错误。所以让我们回去看看有什么
going on. So we have a syntax error here, at the end of the, the flatten method. And
还在继续。因此，在Flat方法的末尾，我们有一个语法错误。和
we see that we left out the [inaudible] to close a conditional. So a conditional has
我们看到我们省略了[听不见的]来结束一个条件句。所以条件条件有
to be ended with, with [inaudible]. Alright, and let's see if that's working
以，以[听不见]结束。好的，让我们看看这是不是起作用了
now. And we still have a syntax error, at line 29. And the mistake here is that we
现在。在第29行，我们仍然有一个语法错误。这里的错误是我们
forgot to declare the type of this variable, which is a list. And then it
忘了声明这个变量的类型，它是一个列表。然后它
gets initialized to this to this big expression that we wrote out. Lemme just
被初始化为我们写出的这个大表达式。让我只是
do the indentation a little more nicely here. And notice, something actually is
这里的缩进做得再漂亮一点。注意，有些东西实际上是
worth mentioning here that this definition here, this definition of the variable
值得一提的是，这里的这个定义，这个变量的定义
list. Depends on the definition of the previous variables in the let. So, each of
列表。取决于let中前面变量的定义。所以，每个人
so when a let binding is made the name of the variable that's bound is actually
因此，当创建let绑定时，绑定的变量的名称实际上是
available in subsequent let expressions. So in this case this variable list makes
在后续LET表达式中可用。所以在这种情况下，这个变量列表使得
use of all of hello, world, and newline, Which we're defining earlier in the same
使用所有hello、world和newline，我们在前面的
lead constr uct. Let's save this, and come over here and compile it. And we see we
引线结构。让我们保存这个，然后到这里来编译它。我们看到我们
got another bug in the code. So, we come up here. We see we I've made a mistake
在代码中又发现了一个错误。所以，我们来到这里。我们看到了我们我弄错了
here. I've used functional notation here calling flattened of next and what I
这里。我在这里使用了函数表示法，调用了Next和我
actually wanted to do was to dispatch to next on the method flattened. So, that
其实想做的就是调度到下一步的方法上压平。所以，那就是
should be written like that. All right, Probably getting close now. Let's see if
应该是这样写的。好了，可能快到了。让我们看看如果
it works yet. Well it compiles and now let's see if it runs. And indeed it does,
现在还行得通。好的，它编译了，现在让我们看看它是否运行。确实是这样，
Prints out, hello world, Just as we expected. Now let's go back to our program
打印出来，你好，世界，正如我们所期待的。现在让我们回到我们的节目
and let's generalize this list abstraction in one way. Let's say that we can have an
让我们以一种方式概括这个列表抽象。比方说，我们可以有一个
arbitrary list of objects, not just strings. And that will require us to
任意对象列表，而不仅仅是字符串。这将需要我们
change a few things so it can be initialized now with an object. And now
更改一些内容，以便现在可以使用对象对其进行初始化。而现在
when it comes time to flatten this list we want to reduce a string. We want to
当需要展平这个列表时，我们想要减少一个字符串。我们想要
present produce a print representation. But not everything in the, in the list, is
演示文稿制作了一幅印刷图画。但并不是列表中的所有东西都是
necessarily a string. And we need a way to traverse the list and do different things,
必须是字符串。我们需要一种方法来遍历列表并做不同的事情，
for different kinds of things that might be in the list for different types of
可能在不同类型的列表中的不同类型的东西
things that might be in the list. And so there's a constructing cool for the type
清单上可能有的东西。因此，对于这类人来说，有一种构造上的酷炫
of, and, of an object, at run time and this is called, the case construct. So,
在运行时，对象的和，这称为案例构造。所以,
let me first introduce a let expression here, we'll let the string that we're
让我首先在这里介绍一个let表达式，我们将让我们正在使用的字符串
gonna construct, Which is of type string. And that's going to be initialized to
要构造的，它是字符串类型的。它将被初始化为
something, and now, it's going to be a case. And what do we put a case on? Well,
一些事情，现在，这将是一个案子。我们要办什么案子呢？井,
it's going to depend on the kind of thing the item is. So the item in the list could
这将取决于物品的种类。因此列表中的项目可以
be, it could be different kinds of types and we want to do a different operation
可以是不同的类型，我们想做不同的操作
depending on what item actually is. So the case item and then the key word is of, and
这取决于物品实际是什么。所以案例项和关键字是of，和
now we have different branches of the case expression for different kinds of things,
现在，对于不同种类的事物，我们有不同的case表达式分支，
that could be in the list. So let's say that if it's an [inaudible]. Okay, so what
可能在名单里。所以我们假设如果它是[听不见的]。好吧，那又怎么样
this does, is this says that if the item is an INT, then we're going to rename it
这就是说，如果项目是整型的，那么我们将重命名它
to I, we're going to bind I to that integer and then we can do something with
对于i，我们将把i绑定到这个整数，然后我们可以用
I. And what would we want to do with I? Well, we'd probably want to convert it to
我。我们要怎么处理我呢？嗯，我们可能想把它转换成
a string. So we'll do I to A 'quot;I'quot; And what if in fact. That item happened to be of
一根绳子。因此，我们将对A‘quot；I’quot；如果事实上怎么办。
type string. The items in the list have to be of type string. Well, then we can just
键入string。列表中的项必须是字符串类型。嗯，那我们就可以
use the item itself, as the string representation. And we can do this for
使用项本身作为字符串表示形式。我们可以这样做
other kinds of types. If we had other kinds of types in our system, we could
其他类型的。如果我们的系统中有其他类型，我们可以
continue to list out other, cases here, and how to convert them into a string
继续在这里列出其他案例，以及如何将它们转换为字符串
representation. But let's just have a default case here. We'll say if it's any
代理。但我们这里只有一个默认情况。如果有的话，我们会说的
other kind of type, which would, which would be covered by having, a branch
另一种类型，它会，这将被有一个分支所覆盖
saying that if it's, of, type object, we'll call it O, then we should just
如果它是Object类型，我们就称它为O，那么我们应该
abort. And so we should just call the abort function and quit. And that's our
中止任务。所以我们应该只调用Abort函数然后退出。这就是我们的
case. It needs to be terminated with a closing keyword called esag, Again the
箱子。它需要以名为esag的结束关键字结束，同样也是
reverse of, of case. And now we can use that [inaudible] we constructed in our
反之，反之亦然。现在我们可以使用我们在我们的
little function here. So if, if the next field is void then we're just gonna return
这里有个小功能。所以，如果下一个字段是空的，那么我们只需要返回
the string. Otherwise we're gonna return this string incatenated with the
那根绳子。否则我们就会把这个被切碎的字符串
flattening out of the rest of the list. Kay. Now there's a couple of things we
在睡觉排行榜上被拉平。凯。现在我们有几件事
have to fix up. We used the I to A method here, which means that list needs to
我得把它修好。我们在这里使用了i to A方法，这意味着列表需要
inherit. From the, conversion class A to I. And there's another issue here, I see.
继承。从A类到I类的转换，还有另一个问题，我明白了。
And that's right here. So, if you notice The, the. The case statement needs to
就在这里。所以，如果你注意到这个，那个。Case语句需要
produce a string. Okay, and it turns out that abort dose not return a string, abort
拿出一根绳子。好的，结果是Abort没有返回字符串，Abort
actually terminates the program, but it's type is that it returns an object. And so
实际上终止了程序，但是它的类型是它返回一个对象。因此，
here we have to convince the type checker, to convince, to accept this, piece of
在这里，我们必须说服类型检查器，说服，接受这一点
code, and we need to get this branch here to type as a string. So what we can do,
代码，我们需要让这个分支以字符串的形式输入。所以我们能做的是，
and this is ugly, but it's the way to do it, is we put it in a block, in a
这很难看，但这就是我们要做的，我们把它放在挡路里，放在
statement block. We call abort first, and a gain, that will just terminate the
挡路声明。我们首先调用Abort，然后调用Gain，这将终止
program. And now we can put any string expression we want after that, and that'll
程序。现在我们可以在那后面加上任何我们想要的字符串表达式，这将
be the, that'll give a type string to the entire block. So we can just put the empty
这将为整个挡路提供一个类型字符串。所以我们可以把空的
string here, for example, and that has to be terminated with a semicolon, since this
例如，这里的字符串必须以分号结束，因为这
isn't a block. And we can close, that, with a curly brace. Okay? So this is just
不是挡路。我们可以用花括号来结束它。好吧?所以这只是
something we have to do, to make the type checker happy. And that may be everything
我们必须做的事情，让类型检查器高兴。这可能就是一切
we needed to do. So let's try compiling this. And we have to include the diversion
我们需要做的是。那么让我们试着编译一下这个。我们还得把转移视线
library. And we have one syntax error. So far. And that's because we forgot to put
图书馆。我们有一个语法错误。到目前为止。那是因为我们忘了把
the, semicolon terminator on, on each of our, each of the, each of the, variables
上的，分号终止符，在我们的，每个，每个，变量上的，分号终止符
that we were introducing in the let. Okay, got to save that. Let's try this again.
这是我们在LET中介绍的。好了，还是省着点吧。让我们再试一次。
And, oops, I didn't actually manage to fix the syntax error. And that's because I put
而且，哎呀，我实际上没有设法修复语法错误。那是因为我把
the semicolon in the wrong place. Actually, I, I forgot. Variables that are
分号放错地方了。实际上，我，我忘了。变量是
bond in a lent are separated by, by commas. But, the branches of the case have
大斋节中的债券用逗号隔开。但是，案件的分支机构已经
to be terminated by semicolons. So, what I said before was incorrect about using
以分号结束。所以我之前说的关于使用的话是不正确的。
semicolons to terminate lent bindings. It's just in case branches where we need
用于终止借出绑定的分号。只是为了以防万一我们需要的分支机构
it, In this example. Alright, anyway coming back to this let's see if it
它，在这个例子中。好的，不管怎样，回到这个话题上来，让我们看看
compiles. And it does. And now let's run it, And it works. Now of course we haven't
编译。事实的确如此。现在让我们运行它，它起作用了。现在我们当然没有
actually exploited the ability to have different types of objects in the list. So
实际上利用了在列表中拥有不同类型对象的能力。所以
let's, let's do that. Let's add an integer in here. Type ints and let's, give it a
让我们，让我们这样做。让我们在这里加上一个整数。键入int，让我们给它一个
number 42. And we can insert it in here. And now we can pass any object, to a knit
42号。我们可以把它插到这里。现在我们可以把任何物体传给针织品
in the first position. So we'll just put in 42 right there. And when we compile and
在第一个位置。所以我们就在那里放42个就行了。当我们编译和
run this it just print hello world 42. If we, if everything goes as expected, And it
运行这个，只需打印hello world 42。如果我们，如果一切都按预期进行，它
does, And that concludes our little tour of [inaudible]. There are a few features
是的，我们的[听不见]之旅到此为止。有几个功能
that we haven't shown in these examples, but you can look in the examples
我们没有在这些示例中展示，但是您可以在示例中查看
directory, for lots more programs - many more pro grams that will show you all the
目录，获取更多的程序-更多的程序将向您显示所有
different ins and outs and details of the other language features as well as the
其他语言功能的不同进出和详细信息以及
ones we've covered here.
我们已经在这里报道过了。